NOTE: These notes are of historical value only!

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

Grex has changed drastically since this document was written. It no longer runs under SunOS on a Sun machine, but rather, as of mid-2017, under a modern BSD on an x86 machine. As such, these blocks are no longer used and instead we use the pf packet filter package to accomplish the same thing.

[index]

Grex Staff Notes: The Kernel Blocks

It's Grex's policy to allow only validated members to use certain Internet services, like outbound telnet, ftp and IRC. A few other things, like eggdrop, aren't allowed at all, while services like finger and talk are allowed to all users. The reasons for these policies are described in our note on Grex Security Goals. To enforce this, we must block the use of certain services by certain Grex users.

This document explains how these blocks are implemented on Grex. Most of the discussion is in terms of the telnet program, but the same applies to ftp, IRC and other services.

Nope, Not in the Wrapper Scripts

If you look at /usr/local/bin/telnet on Grex, you will see that it is really the following script:

    #!/bin/sh
    REAL_CLIENTS=/usr/local/grex-scripts/.inet_real
    MYNAME=`basename $0`
    if [ -r /usr/local/lib/internet.test ]; then
            echo " "
    else
            /usr/local/grex-scripts/no_internet
    fi
    exec ${REAL_CLIENTS}/${MYNAME} $*
  

The ftp and irc wrappers scripts are similar. Sometimes people find these and say "Aha! I've found a way to bypass the blocks. The real telnet program is hidden in the .inet_real directory. If I run that instead of the script I'll be able to telnet out."

No such luck. The script is only there to print a nice message explaining to people why the telnet program won't work for them (and to suggest to them that they might want to become members). The blocks are lower down.

Nope, Not in the Telnet Program

So when people find out that the "real" telnet program that is hidden in the .inet_real directory doesn't work either, we often see them downloading their own telnet programs. Apparantly they figure that since some network services, like finger work for them, the blocks that prevent them from telnetting must be in the telnet program.

This isn't a terribly smart thing to try, so it's no wonder that a lot of the people who try it, do it badly. Some download binaries from incompatible systems (clue: only binaries for a SPARC system running SunOS 4.1 have a ghost of a chance of running on Grex). Others download source code and try to compile it (clue: yes, you are allowed to compile programs on Grex, but be aware that Grex is so heavily loaded that large compiles will slow down the system noticably and take a very long time. Grex's staff is almost sure to notice, so be prepared for some attention. If you want to compile something large here, it is always best to talk to the staff first.)

Those people who successfully download or compile their own telnet clients on Grex quickly discover that their's don't work any one wit better than the one in the .inet_real directory. The blocks are not in the telnet program. In fact, the telnet, ftp and irc clients on Grex are among the few programs that we haven't made any changes to. Please don't waste our bandwidth moving other telnet programs here. They really, truely, honestly won't work. The blocks are lower down.

And by the way, the same goes for eggdrop. We don't allow anyone to use eggdrop, so we don't have any version installed here, but if you do succeed in downloading and compiling the thing here without bringing annoyed staff members down on your head, you'll find that it won't work for non-members for exactly the same reasons that telnet and ftp don't work for non-members: the kernel blocks.

Yep, the Blocks are in the Kernel

The kernel is the core of the Unix operating system. It manages all running processes, allocating memory and CPU time to them. It handles all low-level I/O to all the standard devices, including disks, tapes, and serial ports. It also handles some of the higher level abstractions built on top of those devices. On the hard disks, there is the Unix file system and directory tree, with file access permissions enforced by the kernel. For the dial-in serial ports, the kernel takes care of basic terminal emulation, like echoing the characters you type and keeping track of what your backspace character is. And for the serial port that serves as Grex's internet connection, the kernel provides facilities to make internet connections to remote systems and to send and receive packets. That's the part of the system we modified to implement our access restrictions.

If you are used to older microcomputers, you may think a program could just access the serial ports directly, and bypass the kernel. But mainframe computers (and these days, most microcomputers) can run in either supervisor mode or in user mode. The machine code instructions you need to directly access devices only work in supervisor mode and only the kernel runs in supervisor mode. (Even if you are "root", all your programs run in user mode.) Because of this, only the kernel can directly access the hardware devices, and it is not possible to bypass the kernel. This has been the basic concept behind all real security on all real computers for the last thirty years, and it works very, very well.

Where the Kernel Blocks fit in the Kernel

We don't have source for the SunOS kernel, but all modern BSD kernels are structured very much alike (they all derive from 4.2BSD, which was developed at the Univeristy of California, Berkeley with public funds, and is thus public domain). Thus, if you look at the publically available FreeBSD, NetBSD or OpenBSD kernels gives you'll get a good idea of how the SunOS kernel works (we also disassembled very small portions of the SunOS kernel to confirm that it hadn't changed too much). There are also several textbooks describing in detail how all this works (see, for example, Leffler, McKusick, Karels and Quarterman, The Design and Implementation of the 4.3BSD Operating System, Addison Wesley: 1989).

There are several layers to the implementation of networking in BSD kernels. We are specifically interested in the layers implementing the basic Internet UDP and TCP protocols. UDP is a very simple protocol for sending individual packets (which may or may not arrive) over the net. It is most commonly used for communicating with domain name servers and establishing talk connections. TCP is a much more complex and much more widely used protocol that establishes connections between pairs of machines, over which streams of information may be reliably sent.

The kernel routines handling TCP and UDP communications activity are organized by the kinds of events they respond to:

udp_usrreq() and tcp_usrreq()
handle all requests from user programs, such as to send data, fetch data from a receive buffer, or (for TCP only) to open or close a connection.
udp_input() and tcp_input()
handle the arrival of a packet from another system.
tcp_timer()
handle the expiration of a timer (TCP only).

Before any kind of UDP or TCP packets can be sent or received, your application program must ask the kernel to create a socket in the Internet domain, and it must specify a network address and port number to send or connect to. (The network address selects the remote machine, and the port number selects the service on that machine.) There are several ways that your application program can specify the remote address and port, including the connect(), bind(), sendto(), and sendmsg() kernel calls, but all of these methods result in calls to either udp_usrreq() or tcp_usrreq(), and in either case, a routine named in_pcbconnect() is called to actually save the information.

It is around the in_pcbconnect() routine that we place our wrappers. The wrappers cause in_pcbconnect() to appear to fail if the particular connection being requested is not permitted by Grex policy.

Sun doesn't distribute source code for their kernel, but they do distribute a kernel kit, consisting of hundreds of already compiled ".o" object files, which can be linked together to form a runable kernel. So we were able to make our changes by making some small edits to one of the object modules, causing it to call our routines instead of Sun's, and adding in our own new module.

What we did was write two new routines, called in_TCPconnect() and in_UCPconnect(), which do the needed checks, and then either exit with an error code or call the in_pcbconnect() routine. We then manually editted the symbol tables in the SunOS kernel object files, replacing calls to in_pcbconnect() with either in_TCPconnect() or in_UDPconnect() (the names are the same lengths, so this is an easy edit). The call to in_pcbconnect() in tcp_usrreq was replaced with a call to in_TCPconnect(), and the two calls in upd_usrreq were replaced with calls to in_UDPconnect(). That way, after we relinked the kernel, all calls to in_pcbconnect() had to pass our tests before being processed.

Most of the work on this was done by Grex staff members Marcus Watts and Steve Weiss.

The TCP wrapper

The TCP wrapper, in_TCPconnect() allows the connection to be made only if one of the following is true:

The user has a uid number less than 1000. On Grex, this allows system processes, including root processes, and staff, to start TCP connections.
The connection being established is to "localhost", or to a host on Grex's subnet. We are trying to restrict access to the outside Internet, not to our own systems.
The connection is to a port number on the following list:

43 | whois
53 | dns
70 | gopher
79 | finger
80 | http
113 | ident
517 | talk
518 | ntalk

Thus, all users, even non-members, can have access to these standard Internet services.

The user is a member of group 95, the "internet" group. This allows the people who are listed in the "internet" group in the /etc/group file to have access to all TCP services.

Here's the actual code (actually, it's a slightly out-of-date version, with Grex's old IP address). Note that if all goes well, we call the real routine, in_pcbconnect(). Otherwise, we log an error and return the access error code.

        in_TCPconnect(inp, nam)
                struct inpcb *inp;
                struct mbuf *nam;
        {
             int i;
             struct proc *p= u.u_procp;
             ushort uid = p->p_cred->cr_uid;
             int  *grps = p->p_cred->cr_groups;
             struct sockaddr_in *sin = mtod(nam, struct sockaddr_in *);
             long saddr;

             if (nam->m_len < sizeof *sin) goto Skip;
             saddr= ntohl(sin->sin_addr.s_addr); /* for platform completeness */

             if ( (uid >= 1000) && u.u_ruid
                && ((saddr & 0xFFFFFF00) != (127 << 24))
                && ((saddr & 0xFFFFFF00) != ((152 << 24) + (160 << 16) + (30 << 8) ))
                && ((saddr & 0xFFFFFFE0) != ((198 << 24) + (87 << 16) + (20 << 8) + 32))        && (sin->sin_port != 43)     /* whois */
                && (sin->sin_port != 53)     /* DNS (dig) */
                && (sin->sin_port != 70)     /* gopher */
                && (sin->sin_port != 79)     /* finger */
                && (sin->sin_port != 80)     /* http */
                && (sin->sin_port != 113)    /* ident */
                && (sin->sin_port != 517)    /* talk */
                && (sin->sin_port != 518)    /* ntalk */
                )
                /* if all of the above *and* conditions are true, the user must be a
                   member */
                {
                   /* Test for membership: This assumes that group "internet" == 95 */
                   for(i = 0;(i < NGROUPS) && (grps[i] != 0) && (grps[i] != 95);i++)
                     ;
                   if ( (i == NGROUPS) || (grps[i] == 0) )
                     {
                     log(LOG_INFO,
                      "b_TCP: %d/<%s> denied %d.%d.%d.%d:%d, %d/%d\n",
                      p->p_pid, u.u_comm,
                      (unsigned char)(saddr>>24),
                      (unsigned char)(saddr>>16),
                      (unsigned char)(saddr>>8),
                      (unsigned char)(saddr),
                      sin->sin_port, u.u_ruid, u.u_rgid);

                     return EACCES;
                     }
                 }
        Skip:
             return in_pcbconnect(inp, nam);
        }
  

The UDP wrapper

The UDP wrapper, in_UDPconnect() is very similar. It makes the requested connection under the any of the following conditions:

The user has a uid number less than 1000.
The connection being established is to "localhost", or to a host on Grex's subnet.
The connection is to a port number on the following list:

53 | dns
517 | talk
518 | ntalk

The user is a member of group 95, the "internet" group.

Here's the actual code for the in_UDPconnect() wrapper.

        in_UDPconnect(inp, nam)
                struct inpcb *inp;
                struct mbuf *nam;
        {
             int i;
             struct proc *p= u.u_procp;
             ushort uid = p->p_cred->cr_uid;
             int  *grps = p->p_cred->cr_groups;
             struct sockaddr_in *sin = mtod(nam, struct sockaddr_in *);
             long saddr;

             if (nam->m_len < sizeof *sin) goto Skip;

             saddr= ntohl(sin->sin_addr.s_addr); /* for platform completeness */

             if ( (uid >= 1000)
                && ((saddr & 0xFFFFFF00) != (127 << 24))
                && ((saddr & 0xFFFFFF00) != ((152 << 24) + (160 << 16) + (30 << 8) ))
                && ((saddr & 0xFFFFFFE0) != ((198 << 24) + (87 < 16) + (20 << 8) + 32))
                && (sin->sin_port != 53)     /* dns */
                && (sin->sin_port != 517)    /* talk */
                && (sin->sin_port != 518)    /* ntalk */
                )
                /* if all of the above *and* conditions are true, the user must be a
                   member */
                {
                   /* Test for membership: This assumes that group "internet" == 95 */
                   for(i = 0;(i < NGROUPS) && (grps[i] != 0) && (grps[i] != 95);i++)
                     ;
                   if ( (i == NGROUPS) || (grps[i] == 0) )
                     {
                     log(LOG_INFO,
                      "b_UDP: %d/<%s> denied %d.%d.%d.%d:%d, %d/%d\n",
                      p->p_pid, u.u_comm,
                      (unsigned char)(saddr>>24),
                      (unsigned char)(saddr>>16),
                      (unsigned char)(saddr>>8),
                      (unsigned char)(saddr),
                      sin->sin_port, u.u_ruid, u.u_rgid);
                     return EACCES;
                     }
                 }
        Skip:
             return in_pcbconnect(inp, nam);
        }
  

Conclusion

There is admittedly something fundamentally klunky about hardwiring Grex's administrative policies into our operating system's kernel. It means that if we want to change the services we offer (or change our IP address) we need to rebuild the kernel. But on a system where we give all users full access to Unix development tools, that's where it has to be.

Still looking for an easy way to get around our blocks? Click here.

Document History:

Aug 13, 1997: Jan Wolter (janc) - Initial revision.
Aug 15, 1997: Jan Wolter (janc) - Various corrections and improvements suggested by Marcus Watts (mdw) and Valerie Mates (valerie).
Mar 30, 1998: Jan Wolter (janc) - Various minor corrections and updates.
Apr 14, 1998: Jan Wolter (janc) - Clarified some details about Sun object files based on information from Marcus Watts (mdw).
Feb 16, 1998: Jan Wolter (janc) - Various minor clarifications.

$Id: blocks.xhtml 1607 2017-05-31 16:16:21Z cross $ We welcome your feedback.

Grex Staff Notes: Privacy on Grex

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

[index]

The Grex staff very strongly believes in protecting the privacy of our users. Users should feel reasonably confident that their files and E-mail will not be looked at either by other users or by the Grex staff. It is not possible, however, for us to give any unconditional promises that the Grex staff will never look at a user's files.

This document is meant to describe our thinking about the kinds of circumstances under which staff might look at, or distribute, private information about our users. Rather then describe a rigid set of rules, it is a fairly exhaustive list of the situations under which staff does use root access to look at user's data. From time to time new situations come up that the staff hasn't ever had to think about before. Such situations are handled in a manner generally consistent with the examples listed here.

These situations always require judgment. There are some things that are clearly OK, and some things that are clearly not, but there are wide gray areas, where a staff member must use judgment. Often there is not time for staff members to discuss the situation, and whichever staff member is on the spot must make a judgment call.

Grex's situation is in some ways unique:

Many users are hard to identify with certainty.
Grex has more than the usual number of hostile users.
Staff is volunteer, and does not always have time to handle crises.

There are several common situations may require a staff member to look at a user's mail or files.

Lost Passwords

Every day, several users forget their passwords and ask staff to reset them. Before resetting a password and mailing the new password out to someone, it is necessary to be reasonably sure that the person the password is sent to is the same person who originally created the account. Since many people give very little real information when they create an account, determining this can be challenging.

In all cases, staff first tries to authenticate the person using public information (.plan files, .forward files, web pages, etc) or information explicitly given to staff (the newuser log files). They don't go further unless the user expresses some urgent desire to get back on the account (usually to access email sent there). Then, if the staff member feels inclined to believe that the user is who he claim and if that user requests it, a staff member may check to see if non-publicly readable files have the contents the user says they have, or if there are other clues to the owner's identity on the account.

When a staff member does this, it is important to keep the search as narrow as possible, and not to repeat or reproduce any information found, no matter how trivial, particularly not to the presumed "owner" of the account.

User Assistance

Sometimes a user will have problems with their account, such as a screwed up .login or mailbox file. In such cases, users sometimes request a root to go in and fix it for them, either because their accounts are so broken that they can't access them or because they lack the knowledge to do it themselves.

This is one of the clearest of the OK situations, but some caution is still required. The staff member should get explicit permission from the user, and should make clear to the user what kinds of stuff the staff member is likely to be looking at in the course of making repairs. The staff member should be reasonably confident that this is the real owner of the account, should try to look only at what needs to be looked at, and should not repeat or reproduce anything seen.

Users Causing Problems on Grex

Some users cause problems on the system by doing things like running programs that place a heavy load on the system or attempting to break into the system. When staff notices such things (which may be things with obvious effects on the usability of the system, or may just be subtle things that show up in our logs), it is often somewhat urgent to find and fix the problem. This may require looking into a user's directory without any form of permission from the user.

NOTE: By "causing problems" we mean technical problems, not social problems. No degree of rudeness and unpleasantness would justify any staff investigation of a user's private files or mail. Only actions that appear to undermine system security or performance may do so.

In many cases it is unclear if the user is causing problems deliberately or accidentally. If the user is running a program that slows down the system, for example, a staff member may have to look at the program to try to determine if it could be the cause of a problem, and if it is deliberately so or accidentally so. When staff looks at such a program, the goal should be exclusively to determine its intent and its impact on Grex. Copies should not be "borrowed" (exception: Grex staffers sometimes collect copies of programs designed to crash or crack the system for use in testing our system security), and detailed information about the program should not be repeated to anyone except other staffers.

In cases where the problem appears accidental, staff generally tries to contact the user and advise him on how to avoid the problem in the future. Details of what staff may have seen are not repeated to anyone except other staffers.

In cases where the problem appears deliberate, staff may look more broadly through the user's files to try to get a complete picture of what he may have been doing. Quite often relevant information is compiled and passed on to administrators of the sites the user uses to connect to Grex, and to other sites that may have been compromised by the user. Copies are likely to go to national organizations like CERT that track security problems. Grex staff may leave such accounts active, and may do more than the usual amount of monitoring of the activities of such users. However, even in these situations, staff will try to keep information unconnected with the problem private.

Users Causing Problems on Other Systems

Sometimes staff receives complaints about our users causing problems on other systems on the internet. All such complaints are taken with a degree of skepticism. The staff always tries to figure out who is doing the complaining, and insists on having enough details to judge the validity of the complaint. Staff does not necessarily launch an investigation every time someone somewhere complains about someone. There must be some kind of evidence that the problem is not completely imaginary.

Among the most common complaints are those about users sending email that bothers someone. Staff will readily help people figure out if the email really came from Grex, and will give out information about Grex accounts that is publicly accessible to any Grexer (NOTE: this includes records of from where that user connects to Grex). Staff will not look into any private information in response to such complaints.

Complaints of Grex users attempting to crack other systems may trigger a more thorough investigation of their accounts on Grex, along the lines described in the previous section.

System Problems

Under very rare circumstances, problems with the system might lead us to more-or-less inadvertently see private files. For example, if Grex had a serious disk crash, and staff members were inspired to go to extreme lengths to recover user data from the dead disk, they might need to see some of that data in the course of reconstructing it. Similarly, a really ugly failure of the mail system might require that staff look at the mail that it failed on.

In this kinds of situations, staff members should make an effort to find ways of dealing with system problems that do not require actually looking at private information, and they should not divulge any information they might run across.

System Usage Research

To do a good job of supporting our users, the staff needs to have a good idea of how they use Grex. So staff sometimes gathers of data about how people are using Grex. For example, if Grex were considering eliminating a particular service, the staff might collect information about which users are using it. They might use the list of names to contact the users asking for their input or advising them of a change. They might publish statistics about how many users use a service. However, staff would not publish a list of names of people using a service.

This kind of research should be done only when it serves some direct end. It shouldn't be just to satisfy idle curiosity.

Cooperation with Legal Authorities

If Grex's staff is contacted by law enforcement officials they will cooperate with any legal search for information on Grex. Grex staff will freely give out any public information that is already available to any Grex user (including records of when people logged in and from where they did so) and will assist in the understanding and interpretation of such information. Private information, such as the contents of a user's personal files and mail, would be made available only if a valid search warrant were provided.

Grex's staff will not normally try to act on their own judgments on issues like libel and slander. People with problems of that sort should work through the proper legal authorities, and Grex's staff will cooperate with those authorities.

Though generally the Grex staff tries to keep anything they see when looking at private files secret, a staff member might someday see something that he or she feels must be reported to the authorities. This would be a difficult decision depending very much on the particulars of the case. Grex has no fixed policy on how such cases should be dealt with.

Staff's actions will also in general be influenced by their judgment of how private a piece of data might be. Generally, one should assume that any file that is not permitted to be readable by all users is meant to be private. However, if it is something like a .login file (a file full of Unix commands that is automatically executed when the logs in) then staff tends to be less scrupulous about privacy issues than if it is something like a mail file. However, staff members need to be careful even in looking at things that don't seem very sensitive. Things that don't seem very private to us could still seem that way to the user.

When staff does have to look at private information, the basic principle is to look as narrowly as possible. For example, instead of looking at a person's entire mail file, one would use a program to extract and display only the information being sought.

Remember, it is always possible for new situations to come up, and it is always possible for staff members to make mistakes. However scrupulous the staff tries to be, users are advised to protect their privacy by not storing or sending extremely sensitive private information through Grex (or any other computer that you personally don't completely control).

Document History:

Jun 2, 1997: Jan Wolter (janc) - Initial Revision for staff review based on staff discussion.

Jun 8, 1997: Jan Wolter (janc) - Updated with staff comments. Posted for user discussion.

Aug 21, 1997: Jan Wolter (janc) - Updated to reflect user and staff comments.

$Id: privacy.xhtml 1454 2014-03-26 23:24:04Z kentn $ We welcome your feedback.

NOTE: These notes are historical only!

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

Grex moved away from the system described in these notes long ago. It is now running on far more modern hardware (as of mid-2017 an x86 based machine) and far more modern software (as of mid-2017, a modern BSD). Grex is also in considerably healthier financial shape than when these notes were written, and buys new hardware from various vendors, rather than bottom-feeding used stuff. Similarly, demand on Grex's resources has decreased over the years, as Unix access has become less novel. The supply of Sun hardware that used to be kept around has largely disappeared as Grex moved out of its old home and into a co-location facility years ago. Finally, all of the dialin lines have gone away, as dialin itself is pretty much a rarity these days

That said, these notes may still be of interest to some, if only as an historical reminder of how one group did a lot with very little, and overcame many technical challenges. Hence, it is presented here, in near-original format, with notes such as this one preceeding the information to describe the ways in which Grex has evolved.

Grex Staff Notes: Introduction

This series of web pages is produced by the Grex Staff to describe various administrative and technical matters related to Grex. These pages are meant as a way for staff members to share knowledge and information about how Grex works both with other staff members and the general public.

Some of these pages are meant for the general reader, while others delve very deeply into technical details of how things work on Grex.

Grex's staff believes that good system security should not depend on obscurity. Therefore, there is quite a lot of detailed information included here about things like how passwords are stored on Grex.

We encourage anyone who has comments or suggestions about the contents of these pages to send mail to help@grex.org. Please send questions about Grex to help@grex.org, not to individual members of the staff. Many staffers are swamped with too much e-mail and may reply very slowly or not at all.

Grex's Staffers

Grex has always been staffed entirely by volunteers. Staff members don't have fixed areas of responsibility, but tend to accumlate specific areas of primary activity. Currently, the staff consists of the following people:

Name | Login | Activities
Glenda Andre | glenda | General system configuration.
STeve Andre | steve | General system configuration. Sun hardware. Security monitoring. Reaping expired accounts.
Walter Cramer | i | Conference administration.
Kip deGraaf | kip | General system configuration. Security monitoring. System backups. Reaping expired accounts.
Joe Gelinas | gelinas | Daily monitoring of system performance and staff mail. System backups. Reaping expired accounts. Network configuration.
Bruce Howard | bhoward
bruce | General system configuration. Daily monitoring of system performance. Security monitoring. Reaping expired accounts.
Charles Mitchell | arthurp | x86 hardware. Conference administration.
Marcus Watts | mdw | Author of picospan, newuser, and queuing telnet daemon. Maintainer of grex versions of sendmail, mail, login, passwd, finger, and fingerd. E-mail guru. Network configuration. Sun hardware.
Steve Weiss | srw | Co-author of backtalk. Webmaster. Staff mail. Password changes. Kernel blocks. FAQs.
Jan Wolter | janc | Author of party, write, gate, web-newuser, watch, orphaned process killer. Co-author of backtalk. Staff notes.
Steve Gibbard | scg | Former staff member. Network configuration. Terminal servers.

Past staff members include Dan Cross, Greg Cronau, Tom Dohne, Meg Geddes, Michelangelo Giansiracusa, Steve Gibbard, Dan Gryniewicz, Scott Helmke, Rob Henderson, Jeff Kaplan, Dave Lovelace, Valerie Mates, Mike McNally, Carl Miller, Michael O'Leary, John Remmers, TS Taylor and Marc Unangst.

Several people assist in the running of Grex but do not have superuser access. Ryan Antkowiak (ryan), Eric Bassey (other), Nissa Austad (snow), and Jill (beamer) are party administrators. Morena Vasquez (munkey) is a webmaster. Mary Remmers is the Grex archivist. A number of other users, including Jared Mauch, Rob Argy, Mike McNally, Klaus Wolter, Mark Conger, Dave Martinelli, and Sri (nt) have been very helpful in assisting the Grex staff in various ways, as have all the users who volunteer as helpers, assisting other users with problems.

Staff Notes

A Tour of the Pumpkin
Photos of Grex's computer room, with descriptions of our equipment.
About Grex's Hardware and Software
An overview of the hardware Grex runs on, and the software customizations we have installed.
Grex 2003 Assembly Notes
Construction of Grex's future computer.
Security Goals
A general description of Grex's security.
Privacy on Grex
A discussion of the kinds of circumstance under which Grex's staff might look at private user files or E-mail.
The Kernel Blocks
A detailed description of how Grex's Kernel has been modified to enforce our restrictions on outgoing telnet and ftp connections.
The Password Database
A detailed description of how passwords are stored and encrypted on Grex.
Eggdrop on Grex
A FAQ discussing why we do not support or allow eggdrop on Grex.
Volunteering
Information for people who would like to help the Grex staff, or perhaps join the ranks.
Equipment Inventory
A list of the equipment currently owned by Cyberspace Communications.
Equipment For Sale or Swap
A list of the computer equipment Grex has that we would like to get rid of.
Equipment Wish List
A list of the computer equipment Grex is looking for.

Document History:

Jul 18, 2008: Dan Cross (cross) - Updated to reflect historical nature.
Jun 4, 2005: Joe Gelinas (gelinas) - Updated staff list.
Feb 9, 2004: Joe Gelinas (gelinas) - Updated staff list.
Jul 30, 2003: Jan Wolter (janc) - Updated staff list.
Nov 8, 1999: Michelangelo Giansiracusa (spooked) - Updated staff list.
Nov 4, 1999: Jan Wolter (janc) - Updated staff list.
Jan 14, 1999: Jan Wolter (janc) - Updated staff list.
Jul 10, 1998: Steve Weiss (srw) - Added "volunteering" note.
Apr 9, 1998: Jan Wolter (janc) - Added Overview page.
Mar 9, 1998: Jan Wolter (janc) - Added Eggdrop page.
Aug 21, 1997: Jan Wolter (janc) - Initial Revision.

$Id: index.xhtml 1607 2017-05-31 16:16:21Z cross $ We welcome your feedback.